hi uh Brett contras here just want to
film a quick video to talk about a
couple things that I've learned in my um
my biomechanics course that I'm taking
at ASU um that I thought were
interesting the first uh thing I want to
talk about is about AC biomechanics so
um here I kind of drew a picture here's
the femur this is the tibia and here's
the ACL ACL stands for anterior cruciate
ligament so the um
the proximal attachment of the ACL is on
the posterior portion of the femur and
the distal attachment is on the anterior
portion of the femur of the tibia sorry
and the purpose is to prevent anterior
translation of the tibia relative to the
femur so the purpose of the a ACL is to
kind of hold that from the tibia from
gliding
forward so um as most people know ACL
injuries are very very prominent in
sports and we want to be able to to do
whatever we can do to prevent these
injuries from happening so it's
important to understand the biomechanics
of these injuries um to really you know
be able to try and train um in strength
training to try and prevent those
injuries so here's kind of a diagram
that shows
um the quadriceps um they come around
and they envelop the patella and they
attach um here on the T tiia so when the
quadriceps contract you get because it
wraps over you know around the patella
this is bent you know with a leg bent at
90° so um when the quadriceps contract
you get um a force Vector going this way
so you get like a normal component and a
tangential component um to the force but
it's it's in this direction so just
having the quadriceps contract is going
to pull this way and it's going to you
know provide a anterior force on the
tibia so just having strong quads puts
that ACL at risk so what helps kind of
keep the quad you know the the the quad
contraction in check is the force of the
hamstrings so you'll get the hamstrings
that connect right here and they will
pull uh rearward or um
posteriorly and so when you get
contraction of the hamstrings and
quadriceps that kind of balances out and
helps um you know spare the forces on
the AC so this is just a diagram to help
you understand the forces and one thing
that's interesting I wrote right here
the quads have a larger moment arm than
the hamstrings do to the patella so the
patella here kind of makes the
quadriceps move forward more so there's
a larger like lever length a larger
moment arm of the quads so it produces
more Force so you know you have to have
really strong hamstrings and they have
to co-contract at the right time in
order to spare those anterior forces um
prepared or produced by by the
quadriceps so um strong hamstrings are
really important the next thing I want
to talk about is here's here's an
example um where the femur and the Tibi
are in line with it one another and I
wanted to show how Landing can tear the
ACL
because see how the tiia is angled
downward just a little bit as you land
this femur will want to slide down this
way in this direction because of the
tibia is angle downward so that's how
Landing can tear the ACL because you
would think you know that Landing is
just like this but no it's not because
The Tib is angled downward it wants to
slide this way so you get that anterior
translation with l
so basically what does all this mean you
want coactivation of the quads and
hamstrings um there's some research that
shows that
women um don't have as good of
co-activation as men their hamstrings
are a little bit delayed um but you want
to you want to try and get those
hamstrings to co-activate and to get
strong all right you want strong
hamstrings as both hip extensors and
knee flexors so you don't just want to
train one roller or the other you want
to train them in in both patterns and
you want strong glutes and the glutes
have three primary roles hip extensors
hip abductors and hip external rotators
and the reason why strong glutes are
important is not just to help out as you
know as hip extensors but also the the
the ex the abduction and external
rotation uh strength prevents vus
collapse and vus collapse can actually
lengthen the ACL as well and and stress
the ACL so what does this all mean what
exercises are best think deadlifts
Romanian deadlifts glute ham raises hip
thrust and back extensions those would
probably be the best exercises for um
preventing helping prevent ACL injuries
now the other thing I wanted to
show this is a drawing right here of the
articular cartilage on the distal
femur and there's a split line pattern
um of the articular cartilage and this
this is kind of like what I talked about
with Davis's law being very very
important the cartilage isn't just um
directed in one uniform Direction it's
directed in a manner that's going to um
you know distribute stress and strength
um if you read here articular cages it's
anisotropic which means the strength and
the stiffness are distributed in a
directionally dependent manner this here
the line lines of you know collagen and
the lines of you know the way that the
the cartilage adapts over time is to PR
prevent you know and distribute forces
properly so this is how soft tissue
throughout the body can adapt over time
depending on the loads that are placed
upon it so I found that interesting as
well so that's all I wanted to do um
just film a quick video talking about
these couple things and as I learn more
in my class I'll kind of throw stuff up
like this up every once in a while hope
you enjoy it